Hey guys, what's up? Just wanted to run you through real quick the proposal, um,
and just give you some thoughts on top of it. So, pretty straightforward, uh,
two goals that we had discussed,
really just about making you guys more money through getting you some leads. Um,
this goes into our philosophy about search. Um,
this goes into some more stuff about SS e o, um,
and in terms of like what we'd be included in, uh,
the service that we'd offer you breakdown and proposed work.
So let's talk about search first.
So what I did here was I really stripped this down.
You see we have three sprints here. Foundational sprint content,
sprint link sprint. A full s e o campaign would have content links,
and this would actually probably be about 70 to 80% of your budget, right?
If we were to do like a full six month campaign.
I know you guys had asked me for a long-term campaign,
but I'm gonna get there in a second, uh,
for why I didn't decided not to pitch that to you. Um,
and it's because of the cost in a nutshell, right? So the amount of content,
and I'll show you some examples of the content and the scope of the content,
and then also the amount of links, um,
and how this really starts to stack up and get really expensive really quickly,
um, and potentially just zap your budget and drain your budget.
It's something that I'm very conscious of when putting this together.
So what I am proposing though, and this is completely optional,
we can just do paid, we can just do organic, is our foundational sprint.
So our foundational sprint would be focused on getting a handle on your
strategy, getting all the scope of all those pages that you have,
and then putting together a cohesive plan and strategy to go and attack those.
And that would be at the local level and also at the content level.
So really going through everything on your website and putting together a very
concrete plan, right?
And strategy documented that you could either move forward with us in the future
a month after six months, 12 months, whatever,
but getting something that says this is exactly what you need to do in order to
get on the top organic rankings, right? And again,
a lot of that's gonna have to do with content and your local performance and
also links. So we'd be able to put that all together.
So it's essentially a strategy, uh, and it's highly actionable as well. Um,
again, you could pass that to somebody else as well.
But the reason I didn't put this in, uh, is I'll show you.
So we Google car accident lawyer Atlanta, uh, we see the PLAs,
which we can crush for sure. We see one ad here. Um,
which when you look at the landing page, you know,
I look at this stuff all the time. This is a garbage, garbage landing page. Um,
you know,
I know that we could put something together better than this from a paid search
point of view. There's an ad. Then we get into the local mass pack,
and then we get down here into the organic results.
So this also kind of goes into our whole thesis here.
If you go up and read up in here about our whole total search engine tag,
this is why, right?
Because the top 25% of searched is reserved for paid ads.
We can definitely crush this for you.
And the next 25 to 30% is gonna be local.
This is gonna pull from content on people's blogs.
And then this is like homepage and service pages, right?
So when we pop this one open here, this John Foy one,
you can see this page here. This website crushes it. They absolutely crush it.
Um, the depth that they have here, the content that they have here, um,
you know, we'd want to do something similar for all of your pages.
And you can also see here how they have the who we serve,
then location and then service, right? So this is similar,
a very good example of,
of what we'd want to build out on your website in terms of an organic structure.
So you can kind of get a feeling for the scope of how much content that this
would require in order to get that done. And then even furthermore,
when we take this page, the one that's ranking for a car accident lawyer,
and we put it into this tool called ah, hfs,
what this tells us is the performance of this page.
So you can see here that this page alone for them is driving 6,000 monthly
visits for them crushing it. Uh,
but the other side of the coin here is also the level of authority that this
website and this page has. So they've got over 83 referring domains.
So when we talk about links to your website, right? Uh,
this is other websites that are talking about this,
what your website and then voluntarily linking back to it.
So when you go to our quote here, right,
you can see that we have a a line item here for content and links.
The way that this works with us is that we charge you per piece of content. So,
for example, going back to these pages here, we were gonna scope,
if we were to scope out the number of pages that you needed,
we're talking between 10 at a very low end minimum, right?
That would be for like two locations and the services that you offer upwards of
50, depending on how many different practice areas that we can want to go after,
I'm, I'm sorry, areas that we want to go after, right? Alpharetta, Atlanta, uh,
Marietta, et cetera.
Each one of these then comes with five or six pieces of content that needs to be
associated with it at the product, at the service page level.
So for us to do that, we charge about 500 bucks per page.
So you could do the math on how that stacks up. The next part is gonna be links.
So again, this is just for one page.
And you look at how many links that this one page has, that's ranking first.
They've got over 80 of them. Again, we charge about $400 per link.
So you can do the math there on how quickly this stuff stacks up.
And not saying that we have to get to that exact number of content or that exact
number of links, but that's kind of the basic equation to go with there.
So you can see how the s e o stuff, you know, as much as I'd love to do it,
'cause this would be a great contract for us,
and I know that we could get you the results,
it would take time just because you're entrenched up against some people that
have been doing this for years, if not decades. So that's the search part of it.
Again, this would be kind of like an entry point to just set the foundation,
literally, that's what we call the foundational sprint.
Do all this stuff here for you. And then, you know,
when ready to start investing in content links,
we've got the plan of action ready, we've got the outlines ready.
It's just a matter of, you know, getting a writer to do it. And if you have,
have a writer to do it cheaper, you could obviously do the content yourself. Um,
so that's ss e o. So, uh, and it, I,
it's not that I don't want to do it or underselling it. Again,
I'm just so mindful of the fact of how much you guys have spent and not gotten a
return. And that's really why I like to focus on paid search with you guys.
So again, goes into our paid search overview, our process, um,
we do full tracking call tracking. Um,
so you can see everywhere that calls are coming from, how much you're paying,
what ads they're coming from.
We also do a ton of research and I'll show you how we,
the tip of the iceberg with that. We also build custom landing pages for you.
So, you know, you look at something like this, ours,
we would blow this out of the fricking water. Um,
and I can even send you some examples of stuff.
But if you just look at our websites, um, you know, same designers that do that,
do all of our stuff, um, you know,
you could get a pretty good sense for the design style, the love,
love copy under and explaining. I mean, this website crushed it for us.
This is just one of 20 properties that we own and operate. Um,
so we did the landing page design for you. Um, we'll also sync that with,
you know, your phone numbers, whatever c r m you're using. If you're using one,
we'll set up the campaigns, test 'em, then scale them.
So we do a number of different types of campaign structures.
And one of the reasons why I'm sure you haven't had success in the past is,
is really this one up here, which is discovery campaign.
So I'm gonna show you some keywords in a second 'cause we're gonna do some math
here. Um, but essentially this discovery campaign is incredibly important.
This would be both with LSAs, right? The local stuff,
and then also the traditional ads. So again, going back to the SERPs here,
we would be doing the LSAs for you and traditional paid search,
because not all ads are gonna trigger LSAs, right?
So we'd handle this entire top of the SERPs for you up here. Um,
but the discovery campaign, understanding the cost, the conversion,
the value to the business, we do this at a very strategic and slow level.
So we're making sure that we're not overspending your budget.
So I promise you forecast, and this is what I wanna show you,
this forecast here, and, uh, try not to get overwhelmed here, uh, with the,
with the pricing, the cost. So what you're looking at here is we pull in,
we do research, keyword research, and then we pull it into this.
This is using Google a words planner,
and then it's just kind of like formats over here.
So these would be all the keywords, searches, the clicks, the low bid, high bid,
we average the bid and the cost.
This would be like what you'd pay if you were gonna get this many clicks off of
this, right? So the way that we determine this is the total search volume,
right? Which is all these searches for just this pocket of keywords.
This is probably like 40% of the keywords. It's not all of them, right? Uh,
but the main keywords, quote unquote the ad click-through rate. In other words,
the people might be searching for this 24,000 times per month,
but only 4% of people are actually clicking on your ads, right?
So that results in 960 monthly clicks, um,
for an average for a total monthly cost of $130,000.
This is where I told you not to get overwhelmed. This is a lot of money.
We wouldn't be bidding on all this. This is just to
Kind of get, get like a total addressable market understanding.
So of that front end,
our average conversion rate from landing page to lead to phone call
is 15%.
So that would be about 144 month conversions at about a $900 conversion cost.
So this is what I want you to focus on here. This conversion cost, um,
because this is the number that we're focused on,
all this stuff can be manipulated, right? Because we can either, uh,
given your budget, which we call it $7,000 here, right?
If your monthly budget's $7,000,
then that would result in about eight to 15,
16 leads per month at this price point, right?
At a $900 conversion cost. So that would be at the very, at the highest end,
right? The highest, highest end.
That's why I wanted to present this to you first because you know, again, we're,
we're not here just throwing spaghetti at the wall.
This is a very methodical process here.
We're very in touch with you, our clients talking about conversion costs,
talking about the lead quality,
talking about the ones that are gonna move forward with cases.
So we're not overspending your money here. And I know this number seems high,
right? But again, understanding where you guys are now,
if we were to get you 10 phone calls a month, right? At the lowest end,
the lowest, lowest end, and at the highest cost, so call it $900 each,
10 phone calls, 9,000 bucks. How many of those do you think you'd convert?
Even if it's one of them, two of them, you know, would that at least net you,
uh, positive on the front end or at least break even on the front end, right?
And again, this is like worst case scenario.
So the way that we can manipulate this number down now is I have this filtered
here for the highest average bit. So you can see, I mean,
some of these keywords are just ridiculous, right?
$300 for almost $500 at the high end, um,
in terms of the average bid. So we can do is,
I'm just gonna remove these numbers here and you can see how far that drops
down, and we could focus on other keywords, right?
So to dip the toe in the water, we can do the research and the,
to set up campaigns that are going after some of the cheaper dog bite,
rear end traffic, et cetera, right? These probably have less of value to you,
but allows us to maintain the budget. And now you see at that same budget,
we go from eight to 15 to 60 to 80 leads per month, right?
So it becomes more of a volume game. So I'm gonna leave these back in here.
I just wanted to show you that because this number's overwhelming. But again,
this is a difference in working with a firm like ours where we're not an ads
firm, right?
We're a lead firm and one that's very,
very in tune with not just marketing, but also sales. You know,
I've built and managed my own sales teams.
I know I'm doing the sales calls here, uh,
but I actually have two sales reps here at this business alone.
I have another business that has 10 sales reps. Um,
so I intimately understand the relationship between marketing and sales
and how to get the most outta marketing and the most outta sales and help you to
make sure that you're managing, maintain these leads as well, right?
Again, you make money. I make money, and that's what I'm here to do, man.
I'm here to make some f*****g money. So, um,
this is what I'm proposing to you guys, is to start with paid search. Again,
we can do the, a very toe in the water ss e o campaign too. Get the stuff ready,
depending on your budget. Didn't want to overload you with costs here,
but what I'm proposing is, uh,
$7,000 to start ad spend paid to Google our retainer would be 3000. And, uh,
this isn't like a real pitch, but like the, our, we usually start at five. Um,
so you can even see here the numbers here too.
I was trying to get this number down to a place where you're comfortable with,
but like,
this is what I was talking about in terms of just having us engage at the lowest
entry point. You know, I know $10,000 isn't nothing,
but if I give, give us 60 days. If we can't get you some results in 60 days,
then um, you know, I,
I understand it's another 20 grand that you have to put up,
but you're gonna get some leads out of this, right? Um,
you're gonna get some cases out of this,
whether you're net positive r o i is yet to be seen. But, um,
this is kind of the name of the game. Unfortunately,
in the business that you operate in,
you operate in the most brutally competitive high ticket space on the planet.
And that's, that's why I love it. I mean, I love the competition. Um,
I love how hard it is and uh, you know,
I love cutting off the bigger guys at the knees and kicking them in the stomach
because we're flat out better than they are. Um,
so this is what I'm pitching you guys. If you have any questions, let me know.
Go through the proposal, take a look, have a conversation with each other, and,
um, if you wanna move forward, we'd love to get started right away. Lemme know,
let.